<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Thordal IO</title><link>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Thordal IO</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azure Cloud Platform</title><link>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2021-10-orsted-azure-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2021-10-orsted-azure-platform/</guid><description>Ørsted is an energy company comitted to sustainable development for a greener tomorrow; besides being the biggest energy company in Denmark, Ørsted is internationally recognised among the most sustainable companies world wide.
I was deployed in the Azure Cloud Platform Team to assist the transition from ticket-driven operations to modern DevOps including redesign, refactoring, and implementation towards automated and modular approaches. This also included onboarding new Azure Cloud Platform team members and upschooling &amp;amp; cultural transformation company wide.</description></item><item><title>Cloud- and Data Integration-Platform</title><link>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2020-08-cvation-ftz-integration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2020-08-cvation-ftz-integration/</guid><description>FTZ is a B2B auto-parts and tools reseller, which serves the majority of the Danish market with aftermarket parts, offers 3 million products and had a yearly net sales in 2020 of 2.3 billion DKK.
I was deployed to design and develop a cloud- and data integration-platform to serve as a layer between their legacy systems and their concurrently developed webshop. In addition, FTZ needed a structured and transparent way to manage, modify, and extend business critical third party data.</description></item><item><title>Fire Pump Monitoring</title><link>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2014-03-itminds-grundfos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2014-03-itminds-grundfos/</guid><description>Deployed to develop the backend for a fire-pump diagnostic and -monitoring web application to automate the process of mandatory safety checks on various automatic fire protection systems world wide. The developed backend connected remotely via GSM to the respective units, collecting pump metrics and triggering self-testing before serving the data to the frontend.
The project involved close collaboration with Grundfos employees, frontend developers, and the American IOT-device provider.</description></item><item><title>Fixed Income Portfolio Management</title><link>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2019-10-cvation-imtc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2019-10-cvation-imtc/</guid><description>IMTC provides advanced analytics, simulations, reporting, rule-based recommendations, and integrations with order management systems for financial professionals to manage their fixed income portfolios. Approximately 1.2 million bonds and funds are indexed, resulting in state-of-the-art search and exploration of market data.
I joined the team as a software engineer while the platform was being refined for several large customers. Here I contributed with development on three initiatives, effectively preparing the platform for market growth: improvements to the IMTC web application, a new marketing website and a data engineering platform.</description></item><item><title>Forex Post-Trade System</title><link>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2016-10-danskebank-fxcore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2016-10-danskebank-fxcore/</guid><description>Danske Bank&amp;rsquo;s legacy foreign exchange post-trade system was to be re-implemented as microservices in an effort to increase scalability and maintainability. I initially joined the project as an IT Student as I applied this technological transition as a case study for my M.Sc. thesis. Once I graduated and got promoted, my responsibilities shifted: main responsibilities became development of microservices, infrastructure, and DevOps; additionally I took on responsibility for architecture the final year, focusing on robustness, uniformity, and performance.</description></item><item><title>Hearing Aid Marketing App</title><link>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2015-10-itminds-oticon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2015-10-itminds-oticon/</guid><description>Oticon&amp;rsquo;s marketing department required a revamp of their marketing app utilised by resellers and audiologists to promote Oticon&amp;rsquo;s hearing aids to end-users. Besides providing an extensive overview of Oticon&amp;rsquo;s product catalog and product features, the developed application offered an interactive &amp;ldquo;hearing loss simulator&amp;rdquo; to educate end-users' relatives on the complications of suffering from impaired hearing.
Additionally, I developed a tool to package the app with localized text and media, for iOS- and Windows devices.</description></item><item><title>Radar Service Tool</title><link>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2013-09-terma-radar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sthordall.github.io/site/projects/2013-09-terma-radar/</guid><description>During my B.Eng. I took on an internship as a software engineer in Terma&amp;rsquo;s R&amp;amp;D defense department, as part of the radar tooling team. My main tasks involved developing components for Terma&amp;rsquo;s Radar Service Tool, e.g. components to inspect and diagnose system errors. Furthermore I enabled automated testing for the extensive codebase and set up the CI system to execute it.</description></item></channel></rss>